A Guide to the Alice and Phoebe Cary Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #6978-b
Alice and Phoebe Cary Collection 1852-1870, n.d.
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
6978-b
8 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase, 17 Jan 1964
Item Listing
- Manuscripts
  - "Comfort" by Alice Cary, 1864 Mar; AMsS, 1 p.
  - "An answer to the last verse of Friend Whittier's poem 'The Singer'," by Alice Cary and Phoebe Cary. Autograph of John Greenleaf Whittier also on manuscript, AMsS
- Letters
  - Alice Cary to Mr. Parker, 1852 Mar 29; ALS. 4 p.
    [Congratulates Parker on his impending marriage; mentions a story (her longest work to date) to be published in a Cincinnati paper and, in book form, by Redfield. Also mentions the writing of Elmina, whose story is to be published in the November edition of
    Parlor Magazine
    . ]
  - Alice Cary to "Dear Sister", 1853 Mar 12; ALS, 2 p.
    [Discusses the renting of a house and domestic news.]
  - Phoebe Cary to [Mrs. Thomas], 1867 May 8; ALS, 3 p.
    [Mentions having a photograph taken in Washington. Also received a photo of Mr. Thomas.]
  - Phoebe Cary to "My dear friend", 1870 Dec 9; ALS, 3 p.
    [Discusses attempts made by both Alice Cary and herself to continue writing despite Alice's illness.]
  - Phoebe Cary to Lucy [Carnahan], n.d.; ALS, 3 p.
    [Discusses difficulties of trying to write while entertaining houseguests.]
- Print
  - Phoebe Cary. Typed inscription: Phoebe Cary to John Greenleaf Whittier[originally with ALS 1870 Dec 9], n.d.; Engraving